# Seamus Naaykens

WEB DEVELOPER

snaaykens@gmail.com 825-561-7540

linkedin.com/in/seamus-naaykens-0674 88206

https://github.com/SeamusNaaykens https://seamusnaaykens.com/

#### **PROFILE**

I've been interested in web development since high school, and seeing the field explode over the last decade of my life has encouraged me to pursue it. I previously had a career in hospitality, which helped develop and make use of my natural interpersonal skills, ability to communicate effectively and collaborate as part of a team. Because of my years working in hospitality, I understand and value the customer experience. I am empathetic to their needs and I can solve problems through their eyes.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, Javascript Node, React, Express, MySQL, Agile Development, Document Object Model (DOM) APIs, Web APIs, User Authentication, OAuth, Heroku, GitHub, Jest

#### **EDUCATION**

# BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development

SEPT 2022 - DEC 2022, ONLINE

### Southern Alberta Institute of Technology | Diploma in Hospitality Management

AUG 2015 - MAY 2017, CALGARY, AB

- Dean's List
- Jason Lang Scholarship for Scholastic Achievement

## Western Canada High School | Diploma in French Immersion

SEPT 2010 - JUNE 2013, CALGARY, AB

Alexander Rutherford Scholarship

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Event Bartender/Server | Hotel Arts**

AUG 2021 - PRESENT, CALGARY, AB

- Managed high volumes of guest requests and interaction while maintaining top quality service.
- Guided fellow staff members in setting up and taking down events, delegating tasks to ensure all deadlines were met.

#### Independent Distributor | Enagic

NOV 2019 - AUG 2021, ONLINE BUSINESS

- Marketed a product online using channels like Instagram and Facebook.
- Created successful digital marketing campaigns using Facebook Advertisements to generate sales leads.
- Conducted this online business totally remotely for over a year and a half.

### Manager on Duty | The Loden Hotel

JULY 2019 - FEB 2020, VANCOUVER, BC

- Adapted existing procedures and created new ones to improve service consistency.
- Resolved all manner of guest concerns with exceptional recovery.
- Assisted the hotel in achieving the distinction of Conde Nast Magazine's #1
   Boutique Hotel in Canada

#### Front Desk Agent | Rosewood Hotel Georgia

AUG 2018 - JULY 2019, VANCOUVER, BC

- Employee of the Month-March 2019
- Utilized an extremely detailed property management program to conduct all tasks regarding reservations and check-ins/check-outs
- Coordinated multiple departments to meet guest requests or concerns in a timely manner working with over 120 colleagues
- Managed nightly financial tasks including settling accounts, correcting
  payments and organizing crucial financial documents in preparation for the
  following day.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Co-lead Web Developer | Kandula: Alzheimer's YouTube Assistant

DEC 2022, INDUSTRY HACKATHON IN PARTNERSHIP WITH GOOGLE

 Worked with a cross disciplinary team to create a functioning pop-up/tutorial system designed to give greater accessibility to YouTube users with Alzheimer's and Dementia. The project was completed within 24 hours and utilized Javascript, the SASS compiler, React and Express in Node.js libraries.

#### Lead Developer | GrowLocal

DEC 2022, CAPSTONE PROJECT

Built a functioning full stack web app that is designed to teach and encourage the
user how to grow food at home. The platform connects fellow gardeners and food
growers and enables them to trade the food they've grown with other users. The
project utilized React, Javascript, the SASS compiler on the front end and Express
in Node.js and the Knex library for the back end.